This global warming is killing me.
지구 온난화 때문에 더워 죽겠네!
This is too hot, the Ice Age was too cold.
빙하기 때는 너무 춤다 지금은 너무 덤 다.…
What would it take to make you happy?
대체 어떻게 해야 살 맛 나겠수?
This I like.
나처럼 자리 보존해야지
Oh, no, you won't catch me.
나 잡아봐라!
No running, James. Camp rules.
뛰지 마, 제임스 캠프 규칙이야
Make me, sloth.
꺼져, 나무늘보!
Make me, sir. It's all about respect.
꺼져?선생님께는 존댓말을 써야 하는 법이야
Water ball.
다이빙!
Sammy, you just ate. Wait an hour. Hector, no, no, no, you can't pee-pee there.
준비 운동 해야지! 렉터, 거기 오줌 싸면 안 돼!
OK, there is fine. Ashley, stop picking your...
뭐, 쓰면 말고 애슬리, 코딱지 먹지.…
Pifiata!
늘보 펀칭 게임기다!
Stop! You're supposed to wear blindfolds.
잠깐! 때리려면 제대로 때려!
OK.
알았어요
- Hey, it's my turn to hit the sloth. - Mine.
-내가펼차례야! -나야!
Hey, you didn't have any candy in you.
점수가안나오잖아?
- Let's bury him. - Yeah!
파묻어 배리자!
Hey, Manny, Diego, my bad mammals-jammals.
매니, 디에고 터프하고섹시한내친구들!
Wanna give a sloth a hand?
좀 도와줄래?
Look, l opened my camp. “Campo del Sid.” It means Camp of Sid.
캠프 열었어, 캄포델 시드
Congratulations. You're now an idiot in two languages.
축하해, 되지도 않는 외국어 하느라 고생이 많구나
Not in front of the k-i-d-z. These little guys love me. Right, Billy?
쉬, 애들 앞에서!
Don't make me eat you.
까불면 죽는다
They kid. That's why they're called kids.
애들은 원래 저래 그러니 애지!
I told you, Sid. You're not qualified to run a camp.
년 캠프 운영할 자격이 안돼, 시드
What do qualifications have to do with childcare?
애 보는데 무슨 자격?
Besides, these kids look up to me. I'm a role model to them.
애들은 날 존경해
I can see that.
그런 것 같군
You guys never think I can do anything, but I'm an equal member of this herd.
날바보취급마 나도 가족의 일원이라고
I made this herd, so you need to start treating me with some respect.
내가 만든 가족!
- Come on, Sid. - Sid, we were just kidding.
-진정해,시드 -농담한거야
- Hey, let's play pin-the-tail-on-the-mammoth. - Yeah!
애들아!저 이빨로 이쑤시개 만들래?
Sid!
시드!
I can do stuff.
날 우습게 보는데
Won't give me their stupid respect.
내 능력을 보여 주겠어
I'll show ‘em.
두고 봐!
And so, in the end, the little burro reached his mommy.
그래서 새끼 나귀는 결국 엄마를 만나
And they lived happily ever after.
행복하게 잘 살았단다
- Good job. - Question.
-잘했어 -질문있어요
Why does the burro go home? Why doesn't he stay with the rabbits?
나귀는 왜 집에 갔죠? 토끼랑 안 놀고?
Because... because he wanted to be with his family.
가족과 함께 살고 싶었거든
He should go with the girl burro. That's a better love story.
여진도 함께 가면 좋았잖아요
OK, well, when you tell your burro story, that's what he'll do.
너는 그렇게 결말 내렴
Burro is a demeaning name. Technically, it's called a wild ass.
나귀가 아니라 노새가 맞는 말예요
Fine. The wild ass boy came home to his wild ass mother.
좋아, 노새는 엄마와 노새노새 잘놀았대
See, that's why I called it a burro.
봐, 노새는 웃기잖아!
Could the burro have a grazing problem? Then he'd be more relatable.
내용에 현실감이 없어요
- Boring. - It's not believable.
-열라지루해! -태클걸고싶어
- Do burros eat their young? - It's not a good ending.
-2%부족해요 -결말이 구려요!
Sometimes I throw up.
편집이 필요해요!
They lived happily ever after. You can't get more satisfying than that.
행복하게 잘 살았다 그거면 됐지, 뭘!
One big, happy family. That's the way it's supposed to be.
가족과 사는 게 최고의 행복이야
Where's your big, happy family?
아저씨 가족은 어덧죠?
Then the hungry tiger ate the pesky little kids.
깐죽대는 놈들은 다 호랑이 밥이 됐단다
- You OK, buddy? - Sure. Why not?
-괜찮아? -그럼!왜?
- 1 thought... - Story time's over. The end.
- 아니, 뭐.… - 옛날 얘기 끝났어, 끝!
- Run for your lives! - Where's everybody going?
-조심해! -애, 어디 가니?
- The world's coming to an end. - What are you talking about?
-세상이 멸망해요! - 뭐야?
Fast Tony - he says the world's gonna flood.
왕뱅토니 말이 홍수가 난대요!
Folks, I hold in my hand a device so powerful,
이 제품은 공기를 빨아들입니다!
Gather round, gather round.
자, 거저나 다름 없어 거저!
Pardon me, do you have gills, ma'am?
아가씨, 아가미 있으세요?
So you can't breathe underwater?
그럼 물에선 꼴까닥이네?
My assistant here will demonstrate.
숙달된 조교, 앞으로!
Hey, I can smell the ocean.
야, 바다 냄새 좋다!
What are you doing? I can't sell that now.
코 묻히면 못 팔아먹잖아!
You suck air through your mouth, you moron.
입에 물어, 멍청아!
Through its design and sturdy construction, you'll have plenty of air for eons to come.
최첨단인체공학적 구조로 계속 숨을 철 수 있다는 거!
Of course, results may vary.
물론 결과는 그때그때 달라요
Why are you scaring everybody with this doomsday stuff?
세상이 망해? 원 현소리야?
I'm trying to make a living here, pal.
나도 먹고 살아야죠
It's my weather forecast. The five-day outlook calls for intense flooding
주간 일기 예보입니다
And a slight chance of patchy sunshine later in the week.
주말까지 살아있는 분께는 환불해 드립니다
Come on, don't listen to him. Fast Tony would sell his own mother for a grape.
뱅쟁이 말 듣지 마 재는 엄마도 팔아먹을.
Are you making an offer? I mean, no, I would not.
얼마 줄건대? 아, 물론 엄만 안 팔아요!
Haven't you heard? The ice is melting.
못 들었나? 얼음이 녹는대!
You see this ground, it's covered in ice.
땅이 빙하로 덮여있어
A thousand years ago, it was covered in ice.
천년 전에도 그랬고 천년 후에도 그럴 거야
Say, buddy, not to cast aspersions on your survival instincts or nothing,
잠깐! 내 말 오해 말고 들어
but haven't mammoths pretty much gone extinct?
맘모스는 멸종되지 않았니?
- What are you talking about? - About you being the last of your kind.
-뭔 소리야? -년 최후의 맘모스라고
Your breath smells like ants.
년 입에서 개미똥냄새 난다
Be that as it may, when's the last time you saw another mammoth?
다른 맘모스를 마지막으로 본 게 언제 야?
Don't pay any attention to him.
재 말, 신경 쓰지 마
Mammoths can't go extinct. They're the biggest things on Earth.
우린 덩치 커서 협게 멸종 안 돼!
- What about the dinosaurs? - The dinosaurs got cocky and made enemies.
-공룡은 왜 멸종했대? -아무데나들이대서적이많았거든
Look. Some idiot's going down the Eviscerator.
원 꼴통이 얼음탬에서 뛰어내린다!
Please tell me that's not our idiot.
설마, 우리 꼴통은 아니겠지?
OK, I'm gonna jump on the count of three.
모두 잘 봐 셋에 뛰어내린다!
One,
하나!
two...
둘!
Sid, don't move a muscle. We're coming up.
시드, 꼼짝 마 우리가 갈게!
Jump! Jump! Jump!
-점프해! -점프해,점프해!
Sorry.
미안
Two and three one-thousandths, two and four one-thousandths...
둘반에 반에반에반 둘반에 반에 반에.…
Sid, what are you doing? Get down from there.
시드, 빨리 내려와!
No. I'm gonna be the first to jump off the Eviscerator
싫어, 최초로 여기서 뛰어내린
and then you guys are gonna have to show me some respect.
국민영웅 돼서 존경 받을 거야
The only respect you'll get is respect for the dead.
뛰어봐! 죽어서 영웅되나보게
Come on, Manny, he's not that stupid.
그 정도로 바보는 아냐
- But I've been wrong before. - Geronimo!
바보 맞나 봐
Hey, watch it.
조심해!
I can't breathe. I think I just coughed up my spleen.
숨을 못쉬겠어 백만 불짜리 다리 부러졌나 봐
- Diego, retract the claws, please. - Right. Sorry.
디에고, 발톱 좀 래?
If l didn't know you better, Diego, I'd think you were afraid of the water.
누가 보면 물무서워하는 줄 알겠다
OK, OK. Good thing I know you better.
알았어 난널잘알잖냐
Guys.
애들아
Fast Tony was right.
엉토니 말이 맞았어
Everything is melting.
모든 게 녹고 있어
It's all gonna flood. Come on, we gotta warn them.
다 물에 잠길 거야 가자, 알려야지
Maybe we can rapidly evolve into water creatures.
물고기로 진화해야겠네
- That's genius, Sid. - Call me Squid.
그래, 장하다
This whole thing's a piece of junk. I can't believe I live here.
왜 이렇게 지저분해? 이사를 가야지, 원 .…
What?
왜?
Forget reeds. I present you with this revolutionary gizmo we call bark.
갈대 대신 신제품을 소개하죠
- It's so buoyant, it actually floats. - I'll show you something that floats.
물에 엄청 잘 떠요!
All right, it's your funeral.
죽어도 난책임못져!
See? This is exactly what I'm talking about.
봐, 내가 뭐랬어?
Giants balls of furry lava the size of mammoths raining from the sky.
맘모스만한 용암덩이가쏟아지잖아!
Go suck air through a reed.
그럼 갈대나 빨고 계셔
- Listen to him. He's right about the flood. - 1am? I mean, yes, l am.
애 말 맞아 곧 물난리 나!
Wait. You said there wasn't going to be a flood. Why should we listen to you?
아깐 그런 일 없다며? 널 어떻게 믿어?
Because we saw what's up there. The dam's gonna break. The entire valley's gonna flood.
직접 봤어!
Flood's real, all right. And it's coming fast.
물난리 날 거야 그것도 곧.…
Look around. You're in a bowl.
여긴 움푼 계곡이 야
Bowl's gonna fill up. Ain't no way out.
물이 차면 빠져나갈 곳이 없지
- What are we gonna do? - Unless you make it to the end of the valley.
-어쩌지? -계곡끝에배가한척있어
There's a boat. It can save you.
그걸 타면 살 수도 있지
- 1 don't see anything. - But
-배가어덧어? -하지만서둘러야할걸
Ground's melting, walls tumbling, rocks crumbling.
땅은 녹고 위에선 바위가 굴러 내리고
Survive that and you'll be racing the water,
전지는 물에 잠길 거야
‘cause in three days’ time, it's gonna hit the geyser fields.
사를 후, 화산지대에 물이 차면.… 평!
There is some good news, though.
좋은 소식도 있어
The more of you die,
너희가 많이 죽어주면 난 먹을 게 많아져
I didn't say it was good news for you.
너희한테 좋은 소식이라곤 안 했어
He must have been areal pleasure to have in class.
귀신은 저런 녀석 안 잡아가나
Dam.
젠장!
All right, you heard the scary vulture. Let's move out.
독수리 말 들었지? 어서 가자고
Manny, you really think there's a boat?
정말 배가 있을까?
I don't know, but in a few days, this place is gonna be underwater.
몰라, 어든 여긴 곧 물에 잠겨
If there's any hope, it's that way.
희망은 그 배뿐이야
Manny, let's go.
매니, 빨리 와!
Overturned glyptodont in the far right lane. Traffic backed up as far as the eye can see.
아르마딜로한 마리가뒤접혀 추돌사고가 났네요
And it looks like there might be a fatality.
시체가 많겠군요
I call the dark meat.
누가 먼저 먹나!
Come on, everybody, let's go. Come on, come, come, come. Get in.
애들아, 어서 가자 빨리 타!
- Come on, Grandpa, come on. - We have to go.
-빨리 가요, 할아버지 -시간없어요
Well, I'm not leaving. I was born in this hole and I'll die in this hole.
이 땅굴은 내 고향이야 죽어도 못 떠나!
Do we have to bring this crap?
이 똥, 꼭 가져가야 돼?
- I'm sure there's crap where we're going. - This was a gift from my mother.
-거기도 똥은 많을 텐데 .… -울엄마유품이잖아요!
OK, keep it moving, keep it moving.
계속 가, 계속!
Manny, I just heard you're going extinct.
방금 들었는데 너 멸종된대!
Hey, if you ever master hygiene, try working on sensitivity.
이 주접아, 말 좀 가려서 해라
- I'm not going extinct. - Kids, look. The last mammoth.
난 멸종 안돼!
Well, you probably won't see another one of those again.
다신 저런 동물 구경 못해
See?
봐!
OK, one, two, three... Where is James?
다 있지?하나, 둘.… 막내 어덧니?
Stu. Come on, Stu.
스투, 빨리 나와
Let's blow this ice-cube stand.
어서 여길 뜨자고!
Stu.
스투!
Folks, be the first in the valley to have your very own mobile home.
이동식 주택 선착순 세일합니다!
- Shut up, Sid. - OK.
-닥쳐,시드 - 알았어
Stop singing, Sid.
고음불가냐!
Sid, I'm going to fall on you again and this time I will kill you.
또 깔리고 싶냐? 쥐포되고싶어?
OK, someone doesn't like the classics.
알았어 내참, 음악을 몰라, 음악을.…
What if you're right?
정말 내가 마지막 맘모스면 어쩌지?
But Manny, look at the bright side, you have us.
용기를 내 우리가있잖아!
Not your most persuasive argument, Sid.
별로 위로가 안 될 것 같다
- Mammoths? - 1 knew I couldn't be the last one.
-맘모스 소리 아냐? -역시 나만남은게아니었어!
Extinct? Come on.
멸종? 말도 안 돼!
He's up by a couple of fifths, ahead by a tusk.
네, 매니 선수 열라빠르네요
And he's beating Diego as Diego's coming round the corner.
디에고 역부족입니다!
Sorry. My stomach hates me.
미안, 내 가스가 환경 오염 주범이야
Well, don't that put the "stink" in extinction?
방귀쟁이는 멸종 안 하나?
Manny.
매니?
I need to be alone for a while.
잠시만 혼자 있고 싶어
You go on ahead. I'll catch up.
먼저들 가 곧 따라갈게
One truly is the loneliest number.
혼자라는 건 외로운 거야
These work great.
잘 맞는데?
Cool.
죽이네!
- Missed me, now you gotta kiss me. - I'll get ‘em.
- 우릴 잡으면 용치! -거기서!
- Which end is up? - I'd hide that face too.
-어디가위야? -월굴참구리다!
- Hey, ugly. - 1 gotta sit on that.
- 야, 구린 애! -체질 있단 말이야!
Gotcha.
잡았다!
OK, I'm going in.
기다려, 간다!
- Sid. - What?
-시드 -왜?
- Nice miss. - Cover your side.
-어푸구리! -그쪽지켜!
- felt some breeze in that one. - Smile.
안타깝네요
- Out of my way. - Hello.
-비켜봐! -안녕!
Over here.
여기야!
- Surrender? - Never.
-항복할래? -싫어!
Cool.
좋아!
Smoke them.
공격!
If anyone asks, there were 50 of ‘em and they were rattlesnakes.
누가 물으면 아나콘다랑 50 대 2로 맞짱떤다고 해
- Here, kitty, kitty. - Big mistake, you miscreants.
-약오르지? 야옹아? -요 생쥐 같은 놈들!
Miscreants?
생쥐?
Diego, they're possums.
재들은 주머니쥐야
Retreat.
후퇴하라!
I guess it's just you and me now.
이젠너와나뿐이구나
I knew it. I knew I wasn't the only one.
역시! 나 혼자만 남은 게 아니었어!
Everyone falls out of the tree now and then. They just don't admit it.
맞아, 누구나 나무에서 떨어질 수 있지
Wait. What?
잠깐, 뭐라고?
Some of us have a tough time holding on to branches.
우린 날개가 없잖아 나무 위에서 내티기가 접지 않아
And you were in the tree because...?
나무 위엔.… 왜 올라간 건데?
I was looking for my brothers. They are always in trouble.
말썸쟁이 오빠들 찾느라고
Brothers? You mean there's more?
오빠들도 있단 말이야?
Sure.
그럼!
- There's lots of us. - Where?
-우리만있는게아니야 -어디?
Everywhere. Under rocks. In holes in the ground.
사방에 있지 바위 밑, 땅굴 속..…
Usually we come out at night so birds don't carry us off.
밤에만 다녀 새한테 안 잡혀먹게 .…
Help! Help!
도와줘, 도와줘!
Help!
도와줘
Well, shave me down and call me a mole rat. You found another mammoth.
이런 경사가 있나 맘모스를 찾았구나!
Where? Wait a minute. I thought mammoths were extinct.
어디? 맘모스는 멸종됐잖아!
- What are you looking at me for? - 1 don't know. Because you're a mammoth.
-왜쳐다봐? -글써.… 네가 맘모스 같아 보여서
Me? Don't be ridiculous. I'm not a mammoth. I'm a possum.
내가?말도 안 돼 난주머니쥐야!
Right. Good one. I'm a newt. This is my friend, the badger.
그럼 난 다람쥐게? 앤너구리
And my other friend, the platypus.
앤북경오리
Why do I gotta be the platypus? Make him the platypus.
왜 하필 북경오리야? 재랑 바꿔줘!
- This guy giving you trouble, sis? - Sis?
누구야? 울동생 괴롭힌 게?
That's right. These are my brothers. Possum, possum, possum.
우리 오빠들이야 주머니쥐, 주머니쥐, 주머니쥐
I don't think her tree goes all the way to the top branch.
재, 살짝 맛이 갔나 봐
Manny, brink of extinction's a bad time to be picky.
찬밥 더운밥 가릴 때 아냐
Hey, she should come with us.
함께 가자고 해!
Are you insane? No way.
미쳤냐?말도 안돼!
OK.
알았어
Manny wants me to ask you if you'd like to escape the flood with us.
매니가 함께 떠나재
- I'd rather be road kill. - That can be arranged.
-차라리 죽지! -내가 죽여줄까?
Funny. Let me have a little word with my brothers.
장난 마! 오빠들과 의논 좀 해볼게
Ellie, are you crazy? We're not going with them.
미쳤어?같이 가면 안 돼!
Look, we'll never make it in time if we only travel at night.
밤에만 움직이면 빨리 못 가
These guys can protect us out in the open. What do you say?
재들과 함께 다니면 낮에도 안전해
Why did you invite them?
왜 같이 가자 그랬어?
‘Cause you might be the only two mammoths left on Earth.
진정해, 지구상에 네짝은 재뿐이 야
- He has a point. - Sorry, when did I join this dating service?
- 맞아 -이젠커플매니저도하냐?
My brothers and I would be delighted to come with you.
너희와 함께 가주기로 했어
If you treat us nicely.
대신 잘 모셔야 돼!
See that? That's the total opposite of nice.
봐, 태도가 건방져
Maybe we'll have a snack before we hit the road.
가기 전에 배 좀 채워 볼까
You want a piece of us? Let's go.
어푸, 협박해? 가자!
Banzai!
공격!
- 1 got ‘em. - Back! Back!
-혼날래! -물러 저!
You know the best part? We're carrying diseases.
먹어! 우리 조류독감 걸렸어
OK, thanks to Sid, we're now traveling together.
그만해 시드 덕에 함께 가게 됐으니
And like it or not, we're going to be one big, happy family.
우린이제한식구야
I'll be the daddy, Ellie will be the mommy.
난 아빠, 애는 엄마
And Diego will be the uncle who eats the kids who get on my nerves.
디에고는 까부는 조카 혼내는 삼촌!
Now, let's move it before the ground falls out from under our feet.
땅이 녹기 전에 빨리 가자고!
I thought fat guys were supposed to be jolly.
뚱보치곤 성격 까칠하네
I'm not fat. It's this fur, it makes me look big.
나 안 뚱뚱해 털 때문에 퍼져 보이는 거야
He's fat.
뚱뚱한 주제에.…
Escaping the flood is the perfect time to shed those unsightly pounds
홍수를 피하며 살별수있는 기회!
with Fast Tony's Disaster Diet.
왕뻐니의 홍수 다이어트!
You, ma‘am, you look like a big, fat, hairy beast.
참몸매가비호감이시네!
How would you like to lose a ton or two?
-사모님, 1,2톤빼는 게 어떠실지? -뻐면야 좋죠!
Don't listen to him, Vera. You're already thin as a twig.
저런 말 듣지 마! 당신은 가시처럼 말랐어
l also have the perfect cure for your eyesight, my blind friend.
시력이 광이시네 안경 하나 살래요?
We'll never make it at this pace.
아주 생쇼를 해요
Ellie, it's OK, you can lose the camouflage. You're safe.
엘리위장안해도돼 년 안전해!
OK. Safe? Please.
알았어 안전해?맘소사.…
Crash, Eddie, you two go scope it out.
크래쉬, 에디 망잘봐
- What you got? - Perimeter all clear.
-현재 상황? -이상없음!
- Roger that. One-niner, over. - Roger, over, victor...
-상황종료, 오버! - 알았다, 오버!
- Guys. - All clear.
-안전해? - 그래, 나와!
Hawk!
매다!
- What are you doing? - Playing dead.
-뭐 하는 거야? -죽은 척
- Manny, why don't you do that? - Because I'm a mammoth.
-매니,년왜안해? -난맘모스니까!
But you'd do it for treats, right?
예의상좀해주면안되겠니?
Is he gone?
갔어?
You're safe. Get up.
이제 안전해 일어나
Man.
다행이야
If you weren't here, that hawk would have swooped down and snatched me for dinner.
너희들이 없었다면 우린 매의 밥이 됐을 거야
That's how cousin Wilton went.
사촌 오빠쳐럼 .…
Boy, I really feel for you. I do.
솔직히 난 네가 안됐어
I can't even imagine what it'd be like to be the last one of your species.
마지막으로 남은 맘모스라니.…
- I'm not the last one. - You brave, brave soul.
-나마지막아냐 -그용기가대단하다
That's right. Don't give up hope.
그래, 절대 낙심 마
Ellie.
엘리?
Look at our footprints.
네 발자국 봐
They're the same shape.
나랑 똑같지?
Well, how do I know those aren't your footprints?
혹시 네 발자국 아냐?
Well, then,
좋아, 그럼
look at our shadows.
우리 그림자를 봐
We match.
똑같잖아
You're right. They're the same.
맞아, 똑같네!
You must be part possum.
너, 주머니쥐 혼혈이구나!
You wish.
거울도안 보냐!
Diego, there are whole continents moving faster than you.
디에고, 뭘 꾸물대? 따라와!
We gotta catch up with the others.
우리 뒤쳐졌어!
Hey. Knock it off.
야, 그만해
Cry me ariver, blubber-tooth tiger. Have some fun.
잔소리꾼빼드렁니! 인생을 즐겨!
The ice is thin enough without you two wearing it down.
그러다얼음꺼지면 어째?
Diego, come on. The ice may be thin,
십 톤짜리 맘모스랑
but it's strong enough to hold a ten-ton mammoth and a nine-ton possum.
집채만한 주머니쥐가지나가도 끄떡없는데, 뭘!
Mammal overboard!
나무늘보 살려!
Ellie, get up. If you play dead, you'll be dead.
-눈떠! -죽은 척은 아무 때나 하냐?
Look at me.
날 봐!
Diego.
디에고!
Come on, Diego. Come on.
가자, 정신차려!
This may sting a little.
따끔해도 참아!
- What in the animal kingdom was that? - 1 don't know.
저 무지막지한 놈 대체 뭐야?
From now on, land - safe, water - not safe.
어든 물은 이제 위혐해
That was the bravest thing I've ever seen.
너 엄청 용감하더라
- It was nothing. I... - It's not a compliment.
-별소릴... -청찬아냐!
To a possum, bravery is just dumb.
주머니쥐에게 용감한 건 멍청한 거야
- Yeah, we're spineless. - Lily-livered.
-우린비겁해 -겁쟁이지
Maybe mammoths are going extinct because they get in danger.
너흰 무모한 용기 때문에 멸종하게 된 지도 몰라
Maybe you should run away more.
일단 도망치고 볼 일이야
Good point. Thanks for the advice.
말되네 충고 고맘다!
Happy to help.
도움 되길 바래!
Do you believe her? "Bravery is dumb. Maybe you should run away more."
들었냐?
She's infuriating and stubborn and narrow-minded.
순 왕싸가지 고집불통!
You like her.
재한테 필 꽂혔구나!
-I do not. - Don't worry. Your secret's safe with me.
-웃기지마! -걱정마, 비밀 지킬게
- And so is yours. - What secret?
-네 비밀도! -뭔 비밀?
You know, the one where you can't swim.
물무서워하는 거 말야
- That's ridiculous. - Fine. But we're living in a melting world.
-호리마 -곧물난리가날거야
You're going to have to face your fear sooner or later.
무서운 물과 곧 또 만나게 될걸?
Almost there.
됐어, 거의 다왔다!
- OK. Ready, Eddie? - Set.
-준비됐냐? -오케이!
Let's roll.
굴리자!
Wait for me.
기다려!
No brakes. Gotta roll. Meet you at the other end.
브레이크가없어! 먼저 내려갈게!
So you think she's the girl for me?
저런 애가 내 짝이라고?
Yeah. She's tons of fun and you're no fun at all.
응, 잘 놀고 년 못 놀잖아
She completes you.
둘이 섞여야 정상이지 않겠나
Yeah.
그래
Hey, Manny. Can you pull back the tree and shoot me into the pond?
야, 매니!
-No. - Come on.
-싫어 -한번만!
- You expect to impress with that attitude? - 1 don't want to impress.
-그태도로엘리한테점수따겠냐? -꼬실 맘없어!
Why are you trying to convince her she's a mammoth?
맘모스인 건 왜 강조하는데?
Because that's what she is. I don't care if she thinks she's a possum.
괜 분명 맘모스니까! 두 이름으로 살 순 없어
- You can't be two things. - Au contraire, Man-fered.
이름 둘 가진 동물 많아
Tell that to the bullfrog, chicken hawk or turtledove.
두더지 돼지, 오리 너구리.…
He's never gonna let up on you. It'll be easier on all of us if you just go with it.
재 소원대로 해줘 포기할 놈이 아냐
- So what do you want me to do? - Pull the tree and shoot me into the pond.
-어떻게 해달라고? -확당겨서 연못으로 싸줘
- 1 don't know. - If you're too lame to do it, we can get Ellie.
-글써.… -겁나면 엘리한테 얘기하지, 뭐
No, no, no. No, I can do it. I can do it.
아냐, 할 수 있어
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Come on, come on.
오예, 당겨, 당겨!
- Have you done this before? - Only a million times.
-이거해본적있나? -수백만번해봤지
Farther, farther, farther.
더 당겨, 더! 더!
Perfect. Fire!
됐어!
Yeah! I can fly!
날아간다!
Crash!
크래쉬
- Crash, are you OK? - What happened?
-괜찮아, 행님아? -왜 그래?
- Manny shot him out of a tree. - What's wrong with you?
-매니가날려태렸어 -미쳤어?
- He said he could do it. - And you listened to him?
-많이 해봤대! - 그 말을 믿어?
Crash, whatever you do, don't go into the light.
행님아!죽지마 정신 차려!
Can I help in any way here?
내가 도와줄 거 없어?
You've done enough.
년 돕지 않는 게 돕는 거야
- Are you happy now? - Crash, Crash, don't leave me.
-속시원하냐? -행님아!제발죽지마!
Who's gonna watch my back?
난 어떻게 살라고!
Who's gonna be my wingman of mayhem?
이제 누구랑사고치고
Who's gonna roll in that dung patch with me?
누구랑 똥밭을 굴며 논말야!
Dung patch?
똥밭?
- Wait. My legs. I can stand. - He can stand.
어? 다리가 멀째 설수있어!
-lcan run. - He can run. It's a miracle.
-뭘수도있어! -세상에,기적이야!
Hallelujah!
앗싸!
What can I say? They're boys. They make my life a little adventure.
남자들은 못 말려 한시도 맘을 못 나
You guys are so dead. Thanks for embarrassing me.
둘다죽었어! 쪽 팔리게!
Not the face.
얼굴 때리지 마!
Ellie, Ellie, me too.
내가 이겼지롱
She's not half bad.
재, 괜찮은데?
Crazy and confused, but sweet.
정체성 잃고 까탈스럽지만귀여워
So?
그래서?
So what's holding you back?
왜 망설이는 거야?
My family.
내 가족 때문에 .…
You can have that again, you know.
가족을 다시 만들면 되잖아
No, Sid, I can't.
싫어, 그럴 순 없어
OK, OK, but think about it. I mean, if you let this chance go,
하지만 생각해봐
you're letting your whole species go and that's just... that’s just selfish.
이 기회 놓치면 맘모스는 쯤인데 이 이기적인 놈아!
I think I'm starting to get through to him.
지료 좀 받아야 돼 성질 죽이기!
- Wait, wait. I got you. - Slowpoke.
- 잠깐만, 같이 가! -느림보!
- Need help? - No, no. Just catching my breath.
-도와줘? -됐어,좀쉬는 중이야
- You're stuck. - lam not.
-몸이끼었네 -아니야!
All right, then, let's go.
그럼, 빨리 가자
I can't.
못가!
I'm stuck.
몸이끼었어
Don't you think that picking them up like this would be easier?
나무를 들어올려봐 이러면 간단하잖아
I know this place.
이곳에 와본적 있어
You know, deep down, I knew I was different.
내가 뭔가 다르다는 건 알고 있었어
I was a little bigger than the other possum kids.
형제들보다덩치도 조금 크고.…
OK, a lot bigger.
그래, 무지 켰다! 왜!
Now I understand why the possum boys didn't find me appealing.
어썬지 데이트하자는 주머니쥐가없더라니
That's too bad, because as far as mammoths go, you're,
그거 안됐네 맘모스로서 년.…
- you know. - What?
-왜 있잖아.… -뭐?
- Really? - Sure.
정말?
What about me is attractive?
내 어떤 점이?
I don't know.
글써.…
Well, there's your
굳이 말하자면 .…
butt.
엉덩이?
What about it?
엉덩이가 어떤데?
It's
무진장.…
big.
커!
You're just saying that.
괜히 하는 소리지?
No, no, no, I mean it.
아냐, 진짜야!
It's huge. Biggest darn butt I've ever seen.
엄청커!
That is really sweet.
섹시하게 봐줘서 고마워
What a crazy day.
얼떨떨하네
This morning I woke up a possum and now I'm a mammoth.
아침엔주머니쥐였는데 지금은 섹시한 맘모스라니.…
Boy, Manny sure took a big leap with Ellie today.
우리 매니 진도 많이 나갔더라
Sure did.
그러게 말야
He stood on the shore of uncertainty and dove right in. Splash.
겁을 내면서도 밀어 부쳤어
Kind of brave, huh? The way he faced his fear.
대범하게!
1 wouldn't know. Sabers don't feel fear.
몰라, 난 원래 겁이 없어서 .…
Come on, all animals feel fear. It's what separates us from, say, rocks.
겁 없는 동물이 어디?
- And they sink. - What are you getting at, Sid?
-가라앉을 뿐.… -요점이뭐야?
It may surprise you to know that I, too, have experienced fear.
안믿기겠지만 나도 가끔 두려움을 느껴
No. You?
설마, 네가?
Yeah. Yes, as impossible as it seems,
우리 나무늘보도
the sloth has natural enemies that would like to harm or otherwise "kill" us.
천적이 있거든 우리만 보면 잡아먹겠다고 깜죽대
- l wonder why? - Jealousy, mostly.
-왜 그럴까? -잘생긴 게샘나서지
But the point is that fear is natural.
아무튼 두려움은 자연스러운 거야
Fear is for prey.
그건 먹이감들 얘기지
Well, then, you're letting the water make you its prey.
그럼 년 물의 먹이냐?
Just jump in and trust your instincts.
본능을 믿고 뛰어들어!
You know, most animals can swim as babies.
동물은 다헤엄 칠 수 있어
And for a tiger, it's like crawling on your belly to stalk helpless prey.
호랑이는 이렇게 먹이를 쫓듯 미끄러지듯 나가면 돼
But faster, OK? Now, claw, kick, claw, kick.
좀 빨리! 뻔고 차고, 뻔고 차고.…
I'm stalking the prey. Claw, kick.
먹이감쫓듯 뻔고 차고.…
Il look back over my shoulder to see if I'm being followed.
따라오는 놈 없나 돌아본 뒤, 숨쉬 고.
And I'm stalking and I'm stalking and I'm...
먹이를 쫓는다 먹이를 쫓.…
- I'm falling. - Correction. You're sinking.
-떨어졌다.… -틀렸어, 가라앉은 거지
Kind of like a rock.
돌멤이처럼!
Hey, do we do any special tricks like roll over?
우리, 특별히 잘하는 거 있어?
Or do we just throw our weight around?
아니면 덩치로만 밀어 부쳐?
Whoops. Sorry.
미안
I don't know my own strength yet.
내 덩치가실감 안 나서.…
Ellie, do you realize that now we have a chance to save our species?
엘리, 우리가 종족을 구할 수 있는 거 알아?
- Really? How are we gonna do that? - Well, you know...
-정말?어떻게? -알면서 내숭은.…
Did you just...?
작업 거는 거니?
I'm not a mammoth for five minutes and you're hitting on me?
내가 맘모스 된 지 몇 분됐다고!
I wasn't saying... Not right now. In time.
당장 그러자는 게 아냐 때가 되면!
- 1 was just saying that it's our responsibility. - What?
-그게 우리의 의무라고 -뭐?
All right, that came out wrong. I...
그말취소!년예뻐
Responsibility? Just doing your duty? Is that it?
의무?의무나 다하자?
Ready to make the ultimate sacrifice to save your species.
종족보존을 위해 희생하자고?
I got some news for you. You're not saving the species tonight or any other night.
꿈깨셔, 너랑은 절대 그런거 안 할 거야!
- So, how did it go? - Not bad.
-애기 잘됐어? -뭐, 그럭저럭.…
OK, let's go. We traveled with you all day, now you're coming with us at night.
가자! 이젠 밤이니까 우리가 앞장 설게
But we can't see at night.
우린 밤엔 잘 못 봐
Then enjoy the flood.
그럼 물에 빠져 죽든가!
I can't even look at him.
재 정말 왕재수야
Pervert.
변태!
Making friends everywhere you go. Just making friends.
사교성 좀 배워 어딜 가나 왕따야
- Watch out, there's a stump. - Not anymore.
-조심해, 돌있어! -일찍도 말한다
I thought we could walk together.
너랑 같이 걷고 싶어
Crash, ask the mammoth why he thinks that.
크래쉬, 이유를 물어봐
She said she thinks you're a jerk and to go away.
재수없다고 꺼지라는데?
She didn't say...
언제 그랬 …
Look, maybe if we spend more time...
함께 얘길 나누면.
Tell him that I need a little personal space right now.
혼자 있고 싶다고 전해줄래?
- She said go jump in a lake. - And possums rule.
-물에 코박고죽으래 -까불면 죽는대
- 1 can hear her, you know. - What do you want? A medal?
-나도 다들리거든! -그러셔?장하다!
Stop moving.
움직이지 마!
Thank you.
고맘다
Manny, Ellie. Lock trunks.
매니, 엘리, 코를 걸어!
Now!
빨리!
Crash, Eddie. Grab on to that ledge.
크래쉬, 에디 저리 점프해!
- Funny. Now what's your real plan? - Just do it.
-장난이지!현실적인건? -점프해!
- Bye, Eddie. - Bye, Crash.
-바이, 에디 - 바이, 크래쉬
- Bye, Ellie. - Go now.
-잘있어,엘리! -빨리 뛰어!
I'm sorry if what I said before offended you.
내 말에 혹시 마음 상했으면 용서해!
What do you mean "if" it offended me?
혹시 마음 상했으면?
That it offended her!
혹시는 빼고 말해! 혹시는뻐란 말야!
I mean that, that it offended you.
그래, 마음 상했으면 미안해!
- You just overreacted, that's all. - What?
하지만 네가오태한거야
- Take it back. - There are other lives at stake here.
-그말취소해! -저 입방정!
- He's got a point. - He's got nothing.
-매니 말도 맞아 -틀려!
- It was a misunderstanding. - It was insensitive.
-오해일 뿐이야 -매니 잘못이야!
- Apologize. - Why me? She overreacted.
-사과해! -애가오너한건데!
- Just apologize. -No.
-그냥사과해! -싫어!
- Do it. - OK, I'm sorry.
-해! -알았어,내가미안해!
What?
뭐?
- He's right. I overreacted. - You mean...
내가 좀 오네했어
Not another word or I'll come down there and push you over myself.
입 안 다물면 내 손에 죽는다!
I got it. I got it.
됐어, 조금만 더.…
I got it.
조금만!
Manny, Ellie, run! Run!
매니, 엘리, 뛰어!
I guess we finally did something right together.
드디어 우리가 뭔가를 함께 해냈군
Hey, don't mind me. Just hanging off the edge of a cliff here.
난신경쓰지말고계속해 스릴 있고 좋네
- Remember the good old days? - Which good old days?
-좋은 시절 그립지? -뭔 소리야?
You know. Yesterday, last week.
어제까진 모든 게 좋았잖아
Back when the trees went up and down and the ground stayed under our feet.
땅이 발 밑에 양전히 있던 시절 말이야
Yep. Those were the good days.
그래, 그 때가 좋았지
Possums were possums and mammoths were mammoths.
주머니쥐라고 우기는 맘모스도 없고 …
- We should get some sleep. - Yeah.
-좀 자두자 -그래
Tomorrow's the day the vulture said we're all going to die.
내일은 종말이 온됐어
Wait a minute.
잠깐만!
Can I help you?
무슨 일이삼?
Now, that's what I call respect.
애들이 영웅을 알아보네
Nice.
멋진데?
Somebody here likes Sid.
누군가가내 광팬이군
Who is your decorator? I mean, this is fabulous.
여기 인테리어 누가했어? 감각 있네
Fire King.
불의 신이여!
Fire King? Well, you know, it's about time someone recognized my true potential.
불의 신? 애들이 내 잠재력을 알아봤군!
Let there be fire.
불꽃이여, 일어나라!
If only the guys could see me now.
친구들이 이걸 봤어야 되는데!
This is either really good or really bad.
이거 좋은 징조야, 나쁜 징조야?
No, no, no.
안돼
Me Fire King. Why kill Fire King? A thousand years’ bad juju for killing Fire King.
난 불의 신이야
Super-heated rock from Earth's core is surging to the crust,
지구핵의 용암이 분출
melting ice built up over thousands of years.
빙하를 녹이고 있습니다
You're a very advanced race. Together, we can look for a solution.
우린 유식한 종족이야 함께 해결책을 찾아보자!
We have one - sacrifice the Fire King.
당신을 바치면 됩니다
- Well, that's not very advanced. - Worth a shot.
-무식한 농담마 -농담아네요
No! No!
안돼
Bad juju!
불길한 저주다!
Water? Water!
물이네?물이다!
- Crash, I told you not to drink before bed. - 1 didn't do this. At least, not all of it.
-또자다쉬했지? -나아니야!
- What's happening? - We overslept. We need to move.
- 무슨 일야? -늦잠 어, 빨리 가자
What if we're the last creatures left alive? We'll have to repopulate the Earth.
다 멸종했나? 그럼 우리가번식시켜야 돼
How? Everyone's either a dude or our sister.
어떻게? 다친구나 가족뿐인데.
Hi. Hey, Manny.
안녕!
Wow. What a night. You'll never guess what happened.
매니, 간밤에 뭔 일 있었는지 알아?
You were sleepwalking.
너 혹시 몽유병 있냐?
No, no, no. l was kidnapped by a tribe of mini sloths.
미니 늘보들에게 납치 됐었어
- That was gonna be my second guess. - And they worshiped me.
-어련하시겠어 -날숭배했다니까!
I mean, sure, they tossed me into a flaming tar pit, but they worshiped me.
용암속에 던졌지만 숭배했다고!
You were dreaming. Come on, the water's rising faster than we're moving.
꿈깨고빨리 가자! 물이 차고 있어
I'm telling you, I was kidnapped. l was worshiped. Guys.
진짜 납치됐대도! 개들이 절을 하며.… 같이 가!
Fine.
관뒤라
Can we slow down a little? I'm dying here.
좀 천천히 가면 안 되겠니? 죽을 거 같아
It was just a figure of speech.
꿈깨,나안죽어!
They just sit there, watching us.
계속 저렇게 우릴 보고 있어
I wish I knew what they were thinking.
무슨 생각을 할까?
There. Now you know what they were thinking.
이젠 알겠지? 뭔 생각하는지!
- Sid! - What? It's catchy.
-시드! -입에 붙어서그래
- We made it. - Yeah, we showed those scary vultures.
-다왔어 -독수리들김겠다
It's just a little hot water and steam. How bad could it be?
뜨거운 증기일 뿐이야 위험할거 없어
I just did something involuntary and messy.
나방금뭐 싸 뜨뜻한 거.…
OK, come on.
빨리 가자!
Manny. Get back. It's a minefield out there.
돌아와 완전 지뢰밭이야!
There's only one way to go. Straight through.
이 길뿐이야 뜰고 가야 돼!
Straight through? We'd like to keep the fur on our bodies, thank you.
뜰고 가? 통구이 바비큐 되게?
- We'll head back and go around. - There's no time.
-뒤로 돌아가자 -시간없어
The dam will burst before we make it. We'll drown.
얼음탬 터지면 물귀신 돼
If we go through this, we get blown to bits.
이리 가면 뼈도 못 추려!
- We go forward. - We go back.
-곧장가자! -돌아가!
- Forward. - Back.
-곧장가! -안돼!
- Can I say something? -No.
-내가 한마디 좀.… -닥쳐!
- You are so stubborn and hard-headed. - Well, I guess that proves it.
-년 고집불통 왕싸가지야! -당연하지!
lam a mammoth.
내가 맘모스라면서
- Come on. - Fine.
-가자 -맘대로 해!
I don't know. Drowning sounds like a much gentler way to go.
물귀신 돼서 죽는 게 나은데.…
Blown to bits sounds so sudden.
불고기 돼서 죽는 건 비참해
He's going to get himself killed. Manny, wait.
저러다죽겠어!
Kids, look, the last mammoth.
애들아, 봐! 최후의 맘모스야!
I just heard you're going extinct.
년 멸종된대
- You can't be two things. - She thinks you're a jerk.
- 용감한 건 멍청한 거야 -너재수없대
Where's your big, happy family?
아저씨 가족은 어덧죠?
What's wrong with you?
-내가 마지막일까? -너미쳤어?
Manny, come on. We gotta go. Now!
매니, 정신차려! 피해야 돼!
That way.
저쪽이야!
Do not leave your children unattended. All unattended children will be eaten.
자녀들을 잘 지키십시오 혼자 두면 우리가 잡아먹습니다
- Have you seen a mammoth? - No, sorry.
-맘모스 봤어요? -아뇨
-No.
-못봤어요
Possum? About 11 foot tall?
집채만한 주머니쥐 봤소?
- Hey, buddy, have you seen a mammoth? - I sure have. Big as life.
-맘모스 봤어요? -물론 봤지
- Where? - I'm looking at him.
-어덧어요? -내 눈앞에!
Not me.
나 말고!
Poor guy doesn't know he's a mammoth.
지가 맘모스인 줄 모르나 봐
- 1 don't see her anywhere. - Maybe she's already on board.
-아무데도 없어! -벌써배를 탓나봐!
Hurry, this way. Come on.
뛰어요, 저쪽이요!
- There it is. - Ellie! Help!
저기 있다!
Come on, come on, run!
뭐해, 어서 뛰어!
Push.
밀어!
- You guys gotta go. - We're not leaving you.
-오빠들먼저가 -널 두곤못 가
- I'm not asking. - Ellie, no.
가래도!
Ellie, don't worry. We're going for help.
가서 누굴 데려올게!
Stay here.
-어디 가지마! -장난하냐?
- Help us. - Help! Somebody help.
-도와줘요! -도와줘!
Manny.
매니?
- Help! - I'll save you.
-살려줘! -내가 구해줄게!
Great. Who's gonna save him?
재가 구해주냐?
You really need to brush.
양치질 언제 했냐?
OK, OK, OK. Jump in now.
그래, 용기를 내 뛰어들어, 지금!
Come on, ‘fraidy cat. Come on.
이 겁쟁이야, 기운 내!
You can do this, you can do this, you can do this.
년 할 수 있어!
Trust your instincts. Attack the water.
별거 아냐 난수영할수있다
lam not your prey. I am not your prey.
물을 공격해! 난 물이 안 무섭 다!
Attack the water. Stalking the prey.
물은 네 먹이야 정복해!
Claw, kick. Even babies can do it. Come on.
기운 내서 뻔고, 차고! 이껏, 별거 아냐
Claw, kick, claw, kick.
뻔고, 차고!
Hey. I'm stalking the prey.
뭐야! 진짜 별거 아니네!
You did it, buddy. You kicked water's butt.
년 해냈어 물을 정복했어!
Nothing to it. Most animals can swim as babies, you know.
오내 마셔 동물은 다헤엄친다며
Yeah, but not tigers. I left that part out.
호랑이는 빼고! 그말안했던가?
There he is.
저기 있다!
Ellie, hold on to me.
엘리, 날 곽 잡아!
Manny, Manny, behind you.
매니, 뒤를 조심해!
There they are.
저기 있다!
They made it.
해냈어!
We thought we'd never see you again.
다신 못 보는 줄 알았어
We're gonna live.
이젠 살았다!
We're gonna die.
이젠 죽었다!
- Well, I'm not leaving. - Grandpa, let go of the boat. The flood's over.
난안떠난대도!
- This is my boat now. - Come on, let's go. Come on, come on.
이 배에서 살래!
Stu. We made it. We're gonna live.
스투, 우린 살았어 이제 살았어!
Well, lam anyway.
년 몰라도 난!
I'm thinking about starting a swim school.
수영 교실을 열까?
Sid's Squids.
시드의 물개 교실
All hail Fire King.
불의 신께 경배하라!
Hi.
-방가! -방가, 방가,방가!
Fire King avert flood. Join us, O great and noble flaming one.
홍수를 덤춰주셨으니 저희를 다스려 주십시오
No, not so fast there, OK. You make a quality offer.
그건 곤란한데? 좋은 제안이긴 한데
But Fire King has a prior commitment. His herd needs him.
불의 신은 가족이 있거든 우린 그가 필요해
He is the gooey, sticky stuff that holds us together.
이 진구가상태는 좀 안 좋지만 우릴 묶어주는 존재거든
He made this herd, and we'd be nothing without him.
시드가 없으면 우린 아무것도 아냐
- You mean it? - Sid. Sid.
진심이야?
That doesn't mean "want to touch."
안아도 된다고는 안했다!
Don't ask.
아무 것도 묻지 마
We're not the last ones anymore.
이젠 우리 둘만이 아냐!
You're not coming?
같이 안 가?
You wanna go with them?
저들을 따라가게?
lam a mammoth.
난 맘모스야
I should probably be with a mammoth.
당연히 맘모스떼를 따라가야지
Yeah, unless...
그래, 하지만.…
Unless?
하지만?
Unless I...
난 네가.…
I just wanna say...
그러니까.…
I need to tell you...
내 얘긴, 네가.…
Il hope you find everything you're looking for.
원하는 삶을 찾기 바란다고
You too.
녀도.…
Manny, you've come a long way since we met and I'll take full credit for that,
매니?년 이제 더이상 과거의 네가 아냐
but you need to let go of the past so you can have a future.
이젠 옛일은 잊고 새 출발해야지
- Go after her. - It's OK.
-따라가 -괜찮아
We'll always be here for you.
우린 영원한 네 친구야
-I'll keep in touch. - Yeah, yeah. You're a good friend.
-연락할게 -알았어,너의리파야
Point made. Now, go on. Scat.
됐으니까 어서 가
Our Manny's growing up.
우리 매니 어른 다됐네
Ellie! Ellie!
엘리!
Manny.
매니?
Ellie, l don't want us to be together because we have to.
의무감 때문에 사귀는 건 나도 싫어
I want us to be together because we want to.
서로 좋아하니까 함께 있자는 거야
- What do you say? - Manny, I thought you were going...
-어때? -매니, 난.……
You're possum enough for me.
년 주머니쥐 같아서 좋아
Well, it's just you and me now. Two bachelors knocking about in the wild.
이젠 우리뿐이군 황야를 떠도는 두 사나이!
Fine. But I'm not gonna carry you.
내 등엔 탈 생각 마
- I still have my pride, you know. - Come on, buddy, for old time's sake.
-쪽 팔려 -태워주라
I'll carry him.
내가 태워줄게
- But your herd's leaving. - We are now.
-안갔어? -가족 두고 어딜 가?
Shotgun!
기회다
Manny, who do you like better? Me or Diego?
디에고랑나, 누가 더 좋아?
- Diego. It's not even close. - Told you.
-당연히디에고지 -거봐!
Manny, you can't choose between your kids.
자식을 차별하면 안 돼
He's not my kid. Not even my dog.
자식?앤내 애완견도 못돼
If l had a dog and my dog had a kid and the dog's kid had a pet, that would be Sid.
내 애완견의 새끼의 애완견이면 몰라도.…
- Can I have a dog, Manny? -No.
-나애완견 사줘 -안돼
- Ellie, can I have a dog? - Of course you can, sweetie.
- 엘리, 애완견 사줘 - 암, 사줘 야지
Ellie, we have to be consistent with him.
교육엔일관성이있어야돼
I saved you, little buddy.
내가 인공호흡으로 구했어!
Calm down. I saved you, little buddy. Remember?
진정해 난네은인이라고!